<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Note by Aaron</title>
    <link>https://tinhpv.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Note by Aaron</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 00:41:36 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tinhpv.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Grand Central Dispatch</title>
      <link>https://tinhpv.github.io/posts/grand-central-dispatch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 00:41:36 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tinhpv.github.io/posts/grand-central-dispatch/</guid>
      <description>Overview GCD helps to write multi-threaded code, create threads and schedule tasks on those threads. Main building block: Dispatch Queues, 3 types of queues: Main dispatch queue (serial, pre-defined) drawing app&amp;rsquo;s UI 🎨 handle events (e.g. user interaction) block it for too long, app will freeze 🥶 Global queue (concurrent, pre-defined) Private queue (can be serial/concurrent optionally, serial by default) Usage:
Making a network call, which takes a long time in background queue When it completes, updating UI on main thread.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Note on Memory management in Swift. Always need [weak self]? Delayed deallocation. Get rid of confusion!</title>
      <link>https://tinhpv.github.io/posts/memory-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 00:41:36 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tinhpv.github.io/posts/memory-management/</guid>
      <description>PROBLEM: 1class ProductViewController: UIViewController { 2 private lazy var buyButton = Button() 3 private let purchaseController: PurchaseController 4 5 ... 6 7 override func viewDidLoad() { 8 super.viewDidLoad() 9 10 // Since our buyButton retains its closure, and our 11 // view controller in turn retains that button, we&amp;#39;ll 12 // end up with a retain cycle by capturing self here: 13 buyButton.handler = { 14 self.showShoppingCart() 15 self.purchaseController.startPurchasingProcess() 16 } 17 } 18 19 private func showShoppingCart() { 20 .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Concurrency using Actor</title>
      <link>https://tinhpv.github.io/posts/concurrency-with-actor-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2022 00:41:36 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tinhpv.github.io/posts/concurrency-with-actor-swift/</guid>
      <description>Overview Kind object type, on a par with enum, class, struct Actor is a reference type, similar to a class, can inherit from other actors, conforms to protocol, be generics, and be used with generics Difference is actor has isolation domain, which helps in protecting mutable state, prevent data races Actor&amp;rsquo;s code run on background by default Actor Isolation If an actor instance have mutable property (var), can only be modified on self Can access actor&amp;rsquo;s property, but this access is asynchronous, must use await Can call actor&amp;rsquo;s method, but this access is asynchronous, must use await (even if it is not an async method) Why await❓ To make sure, no other code belonging to the same actor can start, solves the problem of simultaneous access.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Concurrency using Async/Await</title>
      <link>https://tinhpv.github.io/posts/concurrency-with-async-await/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2022 00:41:36 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tinhpv.github.io/posts/concurrency-with-async-await/</guid>
      <description>Overview 1func download(url: URL, completionHandler: @escaping (Data) -&amp;gt; ()) { 2 let task = URLSession.shared.dataTask(with: url) { data, _, error in 3 if let data = data { 4 completionHandler(data) 5 } 6 } 7 task.resume() 8} ⬇⬇⬇
1func download(url: URL) async throws -&amp;gt; Data { 2 let result = try await URLSession.shared.data(from: url) 3 return result.0 // the response data 4} async code runs IN ORDER. No inversion as using completion handler async code can return value to its caller.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Race with Race Condition? Difference and Solution for both</title>
      <link>https://tinhpv.github.io/posts/race-condition-vs-data-race/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2022 00:41:36 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tinhpv.github.io/posts/race-condition-vs-data-race/</guid>
      <description>What are they? Matters? 🤔🆘 Data Race and Race Condition are DIFFERENT
Data-Race → MORE than 1 thread access to shared-resource (can be a variable or object) and AT LEAST 1 thread tries to modify that resource Race-Condition → Order of threads&amp;rsquo; execution leads to wrong program behavior Many race conditions are due to data races, and many data races lead to race conditions. Can have race conditions without data races and data races without race conditions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://tinhpv.github.io/about/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tinhpv.github.io/about/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello there!
My name is Phan Vũ-Tinh, can call me Aaron. I’m a Vietnamese mobile engineer, working mostly on iOS app native development. Besides, I’m also a runner, a travel enthusiast, a bookworm, a pluviophile, and … a superhero movie die-hard fan :)
I’m passionate about learning new things, deciphering challenging problems, breaking impasses, and creating delightful experiences.
This blog was made to learn and to share.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
